A Finding Aid to the Albert Kahn Papers, 1875-1970, bulk 1875-1945, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kahnalbp
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, 1875-1944; Series 8; (Box 5-6, 8, MGP 2; 1.0 linear feet)
  - Albert Kahn, 1888-1942, undated; (7 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 8; 1 glass plate negative housed in MGP 2) (Box 5, Folder 22-28)
  - Ernestine Krolik Kahn, 1875-1939; (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 29-34)
  - Albert and Ernestine Kahn Onboard Ship, 1912-1924 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Joseph Kahn Family, 1894; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Kahn Family, 1902-1942; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 38-40)
  - Family Members at the Kahn Farm, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Home Movies at the Kahn Farm, 1935-1939; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Family Members, undated; (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 43-46)
  - Albert Kahn with Colleagues, 1920-1930; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Artist Colleagues Myron Barlow, Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, and Arturo Toscanini, 1916-1936; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 49-51)
  - Business Colleagues, 1930-1942, undated; (6 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 8) (Box 5, Folder 52-57)
  - Residences, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 58-59)
  - Mattawa Inn, Ontario, Canada, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Walkerville Railroad Station, Walkerville, Ontario, Canada, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Travel Photographs of France, 1937-1938, undated (Box 5, Folder 62-65)
  - Travel Photographs of Germany, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Album of Travel Photographs of Italy and Algiers, undated; (12 folders) (Box 5, Folder 67-78)
  - Travel Photograph of Japan, undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Album of Travel Photographs of Spain, undated; (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 80-84)
  - Album of Photographs of the United States: "Our Trip to Utica,", undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Miscellaneous Travel Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Photographs of Art Work, 1929-1931, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 87-88)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Glass Plate Negative, 1 Glass negatives (Box MGP 2)
  - Five Reels of 16mm Motion Picture Film of the Kahn Family Gatherings, 1935-1937, undated; (from Box 5, Folder 42) (Box 6)
  - Fourteen Oversized Photographs of Albert Kahn, circa 1940; (from Box 5, Folder 25) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Business Colleagues, 1942, undated; (from Box 5, Folder 52) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - An Oversized Photograph of a Business Colleague, undated; (from Box 5, Folder 54) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - An Oversized Album of Photographs of the Edsel Ford Residence Designed by Albert Kahn, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Artifacts, circa 1942; Series 9; (Box 5, 9; 0.4 linear feet)
  Artifacts primarily consist of the tools used by Albert Kahn during his career including t-squares, a large brush, and portable tripod supports for drawing boards used on construction sites. There is also a model of a construction truss designed by Julian Kahn, an honorary doctorate cap and hood, and several monogrammed handkerchiefs.
  - Monogrammed Handkerchiefs, undated (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Three Oversized T-Squares, Three Supports for Drawing Boards, a Large Brush Used with Charcoal Drawings, a Model of a Construction Truss by Julian Kahn, and an Honorary Doctorate Cap and Hood, 1942, undated (Box 9)